Contact

alishaclynch@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alishaclynch (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Safety

Nursing

Patient Education

Certifications

Registered Nurse Temporary Permit

Registered Nurse

Registered Nurse (Single-State

License)

Registered Nurse (Single-State

License)

Ohio Food Protection, Level Two

Honors-Awards

Morrill Scholarship

Dean's List

Dean's List

Sigma Theta Tau International Honor Society of Nursing (Phi Pi Chapter) Inductee

Rotary Club of Marietta Scholarship

Publications

Autocrine Function of Aldehyde Dehydrogenase 1 as a Determinant of Diet- and Sex-Specific Differences in Visceral Adiposity

Autocrine Function of Aldehyde Dehydrogenase 1 as a Determinant of Diet- and Sex-Specific Differences in Visceral Adiposity

Diet-Induced Visceral Obesity in Female Mice Depends on Autocrine Retinoic Production

Alisha C. Lynch, BSN, RN

Travel Registered Nurse at AMN Healthcare/ DNP-FNP Student at Baylor University

Greater Chicago Area

Summary

A highly tenacious and driven graduate student enrolled in the Doctor of Nursing Practice program specializing as a Family Nurse Practitioner at Baylor University (Class of 2023). Future Advanced Practice Provider who is committed to providing culturally competent, evidence-based, and holistic care to diverse communities. A conscientious and knowledgeable healthcare professional with two Bachelor of Science degrees from The Ohio State University in both Human Nutrition (Class of 2011) and Registered Nursing (Class of 2016). An empathetic nurse with six years of bedside experience and proven clinical competencies in acute and long-term care, progressive care, medical-surgical, transplant, complex abdominal and general surgeries, orthopedic, trauma, bone marrow/ oncology, palliative, hospice, cardiac, and neurological

Experience

HealthTrust Workforce Solutions

1 year 4 months

Agency Float Pool Registered Nurse (RN) May 2020 - Present (3 months)

Denver, Colorado

Provide nursing scope of practice and patient-centered care which includes, but is not limited to, safely administering medications and treatment, performing thorough physical assessments, monitoring and assessing patients' conditions, recording precise documentation, communicating with the healthcare provider and multi-disciplinary team, implementing the best evidence-based clinical practice, following hospital policies and state laws, delegating patient care responsibilities appropriately, providing empathetic and culturally competent care to diverse and vulnerable communities

Help satisfy clinical needs throughout HealthONE, Denver metro's largest health system, as a system-wide internal float pool nurse. The hospitals in this

system consist of North Suburban Medical Center, Swedish Medical Center, Presbyterian/ St. Luke's Medical Center, Rose Medical Center, Sky Ridge Medical Center, The Medical Center of Aurora, and Spalding Rehabilitation Hospital. Units consist of cardiac, medical-surgical (med-surg), trauma, neurological, orthopedic or spine, liver & kidney transplant/ complex surgeries, oncology, bone marrow transplant, and acute rehabilitation

Travel Registered Nurse April 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 1 month) Denver, Colorado, United States

Same job role described above in "Agency Float Pool Registered Nurse"

AMN Healthcare
Travel Registered Nurse
May 2015 - Present (5 years 3 months)
Chicago, Illinois, United States

Performed nursing scope of practice related duties, which have been outlined above in "Agency Float Pool Registered Nurse" job description, for a limited or temporary amount of time. Traveled to numerous facilities, as a telemetry or med-surg nurse, to help provide continuous, quality patient care and short-term staffing relief during times of crisis, strikes, nursing shortages, or natural disasters

Partnered with a handful of travel nurse staffing companies including American Mobile, RN Network, Fastaff/ US Nursing, and Supplemental Healthcare.

Types of units include med-surg, telemetry, surgical, long term acute care, oncology/ hospice, and progressive care

Facilities of work experience:

Kindred LTAC Hospital Northwest Indiana (Indiana) -- May 2015- Oct. 2015

AMITA (formerly Presence) Resurrection Medical Center (Illinois) -- Oct. 2015
Dec. 2015

East Texas Medical Center (Texas) -- Dec. 2015- May 2016
St. David's South Austin Medical Center (Texas) -- May 2016- Nov. 2016
Marietta Memorial Hospital (Ohio) -- Nov. 2016- June 2017
Premier Health's Good Samaritan Hospital (Ohio) -- Dec. 2017- June 2018
Northwestern Medicine Delnor Hospital (Illinois) -- May 2020- July 2020
AMITA Health Saint Joseph Medical Center Joliet (Illinois) -- July 2020 August 2020

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital COVID-19 Crisis Rapid Response Registered Nurse April 2020 - May 2020 (2 months) New York, New York, United States

4 weeks as a Crisis Registered Nurse rapidly responding to the COVID-19 pandemic in Manhattan, New York City. Fulfilled healthcare need shortages, helped stabilize the situation, worked on telemetry and med-surg units only, and performed nursing scope of practice care relating to crisis

Mount Carmel Health System 2 years

System FlexChoice Internal Float Pool Registered Nurse October 2018 - April 2019 (7 months)

Columbus, Ohio Area

Provided nursing scope of practice related care which have been outlined above in "Agency Float Pool Registered Nurse" job description

This job entailed "floating" or working in various units at four hospitals throughout the Mount Carmel Health System. Facilities consist of Mount Carmel Grove City (formerly Mount Carmel West), Mount Carmel St. Ann's, Mount Carmel East, and New Albany Surgical Hospital). These units included cardiac, medical, bariatric/ general surgery, trauma, neurological, orthopedic, oncology, observation/ ED hold, or intermediate care

Staff Registered Nurse (General Surgery Unit) May 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Provided nursing scope of practice related care at a Level II trauma center

Provided care to patients status post gynecological, urinary, vascular, and complex abdominal or general surgeries. Some include colectomy, hernia repair, cholecystectomy, Whipple procedure (pancreaticoduodenectomy, gastro- jejunal tube creation), TURP (transurethral resection of the prostate), carotid endarterectomy, peripheral artery bypass, liver resection, appendectomy, hysterectomy, cystectomy, Bariatric procedure (gastric sleeve, gastrectomy), and trauma (e.g. gun shot wound, car accident, physical assault)

Proven clinical competencies in nasogastric/ gastro-jejunal tube feed and management (e.g. insertion of NG tubes, feeding pumps), surgical drain care and removal (e.g. jackson-pratt bulb, percutaneous drains), wound or post-

surgery dressing changes (e.g. wound VAC, asceptic technique, ostomy care), pain management (e.g. analgesics, PCA pumps, reversal agents), intravenous drip administration (e.g. insulin, anticoagulants), monitoring for signs of postop complications or signs of sepsis (e.g. neurological or peripheral vascular checks, frequent vital signs and surgical site assessment, strict measuring of urinary output, obtaining labs), and patient education (incentive spirometer, opioid teaching, advancing diet) or discharge instructions (e.g. how to empty drains, administer tube feed, or take care of urinary catheter device at home)

OhioHealth
5 years 2 months

Staff Registered Nurse (Telemetry Unit)
May 2014 - April 2015 (1 year)
Columbus, Ohio

Performed nursing scope of practice related responsibilities which have been outlined above in "Agency Float Pool Registered Nurse" description. Worked at OhioHealth- Riverside Methodist Hospital

Executed role as a cardiac registered nurse; a nurse that specializes in telemetry monitoring and caring of patients with cardiovascular disease (e.g. congestive heart failure, atrial fibrillation RVR patients). This job encompassed a wide range of duties including supervision of patients status post cardiovascular procedures (e.g. heart catheterization/ angioplasty, cardioversion, transesophageal echocardiogram, pacemaker or cardioverter-defibrillator insertion), safely initiating and maintaining cardiac drips (e.g. antiarrhythmics, antihypertensives, diuretics, anticoagulants, vasopressors), provide cardiac teaching (e.g. strict sodium and fluid restriction diet, monitoring daily weights), continuously monitoring patients' telemetry (e.g. performing and interpreting ECGs, identifying heart arrhythmias), monitoring or obtaining labs (e.g. drawing ABGs, monitoring cardiac enzymes, electrolyte replacement), and sometimes "float" to the open heart surgery floor (e.g. sternal precautions, ambulating, incision assessment/ care)

Patient Care Technician (PCT)/ Nursing Assistant (Telemetry Unit) November 2011 - May 2014 (2 years 7 months) Columbus, Ohio

Performed tasks under the supervision of the Registered Nurse, at OhioHealth-Riverside Methodist Hospital, which included, but not limited to, obtaining vital signs and blood glucose, operating the ECG machine, transporting patients throughout the hospital, monitoring patients on telemetry or continuous pulse

oximetry, providing basic personal hygiene such as dressing or bathing, safely feeding patients, and ambulating with individuals who needed additional assistance

Patient Care Companion/ Hospital Sitter
October 2010 - November 2011 (1 year 2 months)
Columbus, Ohio, United States

Worked throughout the OhioHealth hospital system (Dublin Methodist, Grant Medical Center, Riverside Methodist, Doctor's Hospital, Grady Memorial Hospital) as a "sitter" or patient companion. Role included closely monitoring suicidal or confused patients, providing 1:1 care, notifying the nurse if the patient was attempting to pull out intravenous or indwelling catheters, and lastly bringing forth companionship and empathy

Patient Nutrition Advocate / Nutrition Aide March 2010 - November 2011 (1 year 9 months) Columbus, Ohio

Worked closely with the dietitian and food services department to create the best meal plan for each patient, adjusted individual diets based on diagnosis and/ or medical history, provided education regarding nutritious meal options or limitations of their specific diet, delivered timely meal trays, calculated carbohydrate count and liquids consumed, and implemented food safety and protection guidelines

The Ohio State University College of Education and Human Ecology 1 year

Student Research Assistant in the Department of Nutrition, Human Sciences 2010 - 2011 (1 year)

Participated in research at the Ohio State University's Department of Nutrition under the supervision of Dr. O. Ziouzenkova. "We investigated the role of retinoic acid (RA) production by aldehyde dehydrogenase 1 (Aldh1a1, - a2, and -a3), the major RA-producing enzymes, on sex-specific fat depot formation" (Yasmeen et al., 2013, p. 124). Provided evidence that Aldh1 does in fact play a role in fat formation (visceral vs. subcutaneous) dependent on gender (female vs. male) and dietary differences (regular vs. high fat diet). "Our data suggest that Aldh1 is a potential target for sex-specific antiobesity therapy" (Yasmeen et al., 2013, p. 124) in the future.

Fundraising Chairperson of the Food and Nutrition Forum 2010 - 2011 (1 year)

Member of Global Nutrition Club 2010 - 2011 (1 year)

The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center Student Information Associate 2009 - 2011 (2 years)

Ohio Department of Health Student Research Intern 2010 - 2010 (less than a year) Columbus, Ohio Area

Interned at the Ohio Department of Health (ODH) with the Office of Health Improvement and Wellness with an initiative called Creating Health Communities (CHC). Utilized the resources of ODH to help research health disparities in all sectors of Ohio as well as helped fulfill CHC's mission to prevent and reduce chronic disease, implement the best evidence-based practices, and provide access and affordability to healthy lifestyle opportunities

Ohio State University College of Food, Agricultural, and Environmental Sciences

1 year

Student Food Sensory Analyst in the Department of Food Science and Technology

2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Set-up taste testing studies which included, but not limited to, preparation of food products for sampling (heating up and labeling samples), observation of subjects tasting foods, and participation in analyzing new food specimens (critiquing sensory characteristics like taste, texture, appearance, and smell)

Administrative Assistant to Program Manager of Office of Diversity, Equity and Inclusion at OSU 2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Education

Baylor University

Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP), Advanced Practice Registered Nurse (APRN)/ Family Nurse Practitioner (FNP) · (2020 - 2023)

The Ohio State University

Bachelor of Science (BSN), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (2015 - 2016)

Chamberlain University

Registered Nursing/ Registered Nurse (RN) · (2012 - 2014)

The Ohio State University

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Human Nutrition (Nutrition in Industry, Business minor) · (2006 - 2011)